lifetime.life 2019-03-26

# Privacy Policy

Effective December 17, 2018  

**LIFE TIME PRIVACY POLICY**

Last Updated: December 17th, 2018.

Life Time respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal information.

This Privacy Policy (“ **Policy** ”) describes the way Life Time, or any of its affiliates or subsidiaries (“ **Life Time** ”) collects, uses, processes, maintains, and discloses information gathered from the use of our websites (including lifetime.life, mylt.life), mobile apps, products, subscriptions (such as for _Experience Life_ magazine), and all other services (collectively, “ **Services** ”). This includes information associated with a person that may identify them as an individual (“ **Personal Data** ”) as well as information that cannot be used to identify an individual (“ **Non-Personal Data** ”). The limitations and requirements in this Policy on our collection, use, processing, disclosure, transfer, storage, and retention of Personal Data do not apply to Non-Personal Data.

To the extent Life Time provides you notice of different or additional privacy policies or practices, those additional terms will govern the collection and use of data. By using any of our Services, you agree to the practices outlined below regarding Life Time’s treatment of your personal information.

**Table of Contents**

1.     Personal Data We Collect  
2.     How We Use the Personal Data We Collect  
3.     How We Disclose and Transfer Your Personal Data  
4.     Health Information Privacy Notice  
5.     How We Secure Your Personal Data  
6.     Choices You Have Regarding Your Personal Data  
7.     Retention of Your Personal Data  
8.     Cookies, Web Beacons, and Other Technologies  
9.     Children  
10.   International Privacy Laws  
11.   Terms of Service  
12.   Exclusions  
13.   Changes to This Privacy Policy  
14.   Contacting Us  
15.   Your California Privacy Rights

1.     **Personal Data We Collect**  
1.1    **Personal Data You Provide Us.**  
You voluntarily provide Life Time with Personal Data when signing up to use Life Time’s Services. This Personal Data may include  your contact information, such as your first and last name, email, postal address, and phone number; a username and password; date of birth; social media account(s) information; payment and billing information; geo-location; emergency contact information; biometric information, images, videos, photographs, sounds and other materials in public forums; member interest groups, member number, classes, programs, events, and activities you participate in through our clubs, and/or information you include in public forums, messages, comments, searches, or queries through the Services.

From time to time, we may run a sweepstakes or contest through our Services, or ask you to complete questionnaires or surveys. We use the information you provide to administer the sweepstakes, contest, or survey, to analyze the results, for research purposes, to send you other information or offers we think may be of interest to you, to comply with legal requirements, and for other purposes as described in this Policy.

1.2    **Personal Data We Collect Automatically**  
Life Time automatically collects some Personal Data as you use our Services. This Personal Data includes your internet protocol (“ **IP** ”) addresses; your device and browser type; your internet service provider (“ **ISP** ”); your operating systems; statistics on your activities through the Services; information about how you came to our Services; date and time stamps, advertising metrics; and information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies as described under “7. Cookies, Web Beacons, and Other Technologies.”

1.3    **Personal Data We Collect From Third Parties**  
Life Time may also collect Personal Data about you from third-party sources such as strategic partners, service providers, social media platforms, and other commercially and publically available sources. This information from third parties may be combined with Personal Data that Life Time collects about you.

You may be able to link your account with certain third party applications, such as Google. When you link your account to these third party applications, Life Time requests permission to access your basic information such as your name, profile picture, gender, networks, user ID, list of friends, and any other public information linked to your account on that application. For more information regarding linking your account with third party applications, please see “3.7 Third Party Applications.”

1.4    **Personal Data From Your Mobile Device**  
Life Time may provide additional features on mobile applications that rely on the use of additional information from your mobile device or require access to certain services through your mobile device. These features enhance your mobile application experience, but are not required to use the Service. Granting Life Time access to this information does not grant Life Time unlimited access to that information. Life Time will not access this information without your permission. Some Personal Data from your mobile device, such as your mobile device ID, your operation system, your mobile carrier, and your IP address, are collected automatically when you use our Services. When using our Services through your mobile device, Life Time requests permission to obtain your current location to provide you with location-related services. Life Time may also request permission to access your contacts list or email addresses saved on your mobile device. In the “Settings” function on your phone, you have the ability to manually permit or preclude Life Time from recording your geolocation information, as well as access to your contacts and email addresses, for certain features of the Services.

1.5    **Your Personal Health Information**  
Personal Health Information (“ **PHI** ”) means any information, including demographic information, collected from an individual that (1) is created or received by a health care provider or employer, or (2) relates to the past present or future physical or mental health condition of an individual and can identify that individual. This includes information about the health care you receive and amounts paid for that health care. Please see “4. Health Information Privacy Notice” for more information regarding the collection, use and protection of your health information.

2.     **How We Use the Personal Data We Collect**  
2.1    **Your Account**  
Life Time may use Personal Data, such as your name, address, phone number, and email address, to register your account for certain Services, to communicate important information to you, to register you for events, classes, or programs, to send you service-related notifications and scheduling confirmations, to improve our Services by providing personalized experiences, location customization, personalized help and instructions, and for other customer service purposes. We may obtain additional Personal Data about you to keep our records current.

Life Time occasionally collects information on behalf of third parties. This data may be subject to contractual requirements that limits Life Time’s ability to use and transfer your information in a more narrow way than this Policy. In these limited circumstances, your information is subject to those contractual requirements and not to this Policy. These requirements may include separate enforcement by the applicable third party. If your information is collected on behalf of a third party, it will be evident at the time you provide such information. This Policy does not cover a third party’s use of your information outside of Life Time’s Services.

2.2    **Our Business Use**  
Life Time may use your Personal Data for internal business purposes, including helping us improve the content and functionality of our Services, to better understand our users and how they use our Services, to improve the Services we offer, to develop new features or services, to manage your account, to provide you with customer service, to improve our security and prevent fraud, to comply with all legal obligations and rights, and to generally manage the Services and our business.

2.3    **Communications, Subscriptions, and Marketing**  
We may use your Personal Data for communication purposes to fulfill subscription, respond to information opt-in requests, update you about our Services, send you electronic or SMS alerts or account notifications regarding events, newsletters, e-newsletters, promotions, and to send offers for third party products and services. You may also receive promotional or marketing materials via electronic communication, as well as displayed content and advertising on or off the Services that maybe of interest to you. Your Personal Data may be used to assist us in advertising our Services on third party websites. For further information regarding electronic communications, please see “6.3 Opting Out of Electronic Communications.”

3.     **How We Disclose and Transfer Your Personal Data**  
3.1    **Not Selling Your Personal Data**  
Your trust in us regarding the use of your Personal Data is an important part of our relationship with you. Therefore, we will not sell your Personal Data to third parties, including third party advertisers without your prior consent. There are some circumstances, however, where we may disclose, transfer, or share your Personal Data with a third party without notice to you, as described below.

3.2    **Business Transfers**  
Life Time may decide to sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution, or similar event, Personal Data may be considered part of the transferred assets. By using our Services, you agree that any successor to Life Time will continue to have the right to use your Personal Data in accordance with this Policy.

3.3    **Parent Companies, Subsidiaries, and Affiliates**  
We may share your Personal Data with our parent companies, subsidiaries, or affiliates for purposes according to this Policy. Any Personal Data shared with our parent companies, subsidiaries, or affiliates will comply with this Policy.

3.4    **Contractors, Consultants, and Service Providers**  
We may share your Personal Data with our contractors, consultants, and service providers who process Personal Data on behalf of Life Time to perform certain business-related functions and may be located wherever Life Time operates. These companies may include marketing agencies, subscription fulfillment centers, database service providers, backup and disaster recovery service providers, email service providers, payment processors, providers who help to fulfill product or service orders, and others. Access to your Personal Data by these companies is limited to information necessary to successfully perform business-related functions. These companies must agree to maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of all Personal Data in accordance with this Policy.

3.5    **Marketing Partners**  
Life Time may disclose your Personal Data to third parties with whom we have marketing, promotional, or other advertising relationships. These third parties may use your information for marketing purposes, such as to market products and services they believe would be of interest to you. We may combine the Personal Data that we collect about you with other information from third parties. This information is used to determine what advertisements to direct to you, to place on our websites, and where to advertise our Services. You have the ability to opt out of certain uses of your information, as well as to opt-into receiving information as discussed in “6.3 Opting out of Electronic Communications.” These third parties may also use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons, and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. For further information about the use of third party technologies, please see “7. Cookies, Web Beacons, Etc.”

3.6    **Third Party Applications**  
Some of our services allow you to connect your Life Time account to third party services, such as Google when adding events to a Google calendar, through Single Sign On authorization (“ **SSO** ”). Choosing to connect your account with a third party application may allow third parties to access Personal Data, including your name, email address, location, and age. This connection may also allow third parties to collect your IP address, which aspects of our Services you use, and may set a cookie for its features to function properly. Additionally, that third party application may share your Personal Data. Depending on the application, your ability to adjust your account settings and share your Personal Data may reside in our Services or within the third party application. Be aware that your ability to use SSO with third party applications may be impacted by any limitations you set with your Personal Data.

A third party’s application’s use of information collected from you is governed by the third party application’s privacy policy and your settings on its service. Life Time is not responsible for the collection and use of your information by third party applications.

3.7    **Legal Requirements**  
Life Time may disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law in order to respond to a subpoena or request from law enforcement, a court, or a government agency, including in response to public authorities to meet national security or law enforcement requirements, or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) comply with a legal obligation, (ii) protect or defend our rights, interests, or property, or that of third parties, (iii) prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with our Services, (iv) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of our Services or the public, or (v) protect against legal liability.

4.     **How We Secure Your Personal Data**  
We take your security seriously and strive to take reasonable steps to protect your information. No data transmission over the internet or information storage technology can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. The following is a summary of the measures we take to protect your Personal Data and an explanation of the ways we implement these measures. We continue to evaluate and implement enhancements in security technology and practices, however we can only take steps to help reduce the risks of unauthorized access. There are also steps you can take to protect your information and further minimize the likelihood of a security incident.

4.1    **Secure Socket Layer**  
We use Secure Socket Layer (“ **SSL** ”) encryption when transmitting certain kinds of information, such as payment information or Personal Data. An icon resembling a padlock is displayed in most browsers’ window or address bar during SSL transactions. For example, if you choose to store or enter your credit card number in our Services, it will not be displayed back in entirety for any users. Instead of the entire number, you will only see asterisks and either the first four digits or the last four digits of your number.

4.2    **Secure Storage**  
We maintain reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to protect personal information about you.

4.3    V **endors and Partners**  
We work with vendors and partners to protect the security and privacy of user information. We also use cloud services, such as Amazon AWS, to host our Services. These cloud service providers maintain their own procedures and controls to ensure data security. For further information regarding cloud services we may use, please email [privacy@lt.life](mailto:privacy@lt.life).

4.4    **Employee and Contractor Access to Personal Data**  
We limit access to personal information about you only to trained employees who we reasonably believe need to come into contact with that information to provide products and services to you in order to do their jobs.

5.     **Choices You Have Regarding Your Personal Data**  
5.1    **Accessing, Updating, Correcting, or Deleting Your Personal Data**  
You may review, correct, and update some of your Personal Data related to your membership on myLT.com or myltplan.com. You may submit a written request to either the email or mailing address listed under “14. Contacting Us” to ask what Personal Data Life Time maintains, how it is being used, and with whom, if anyone, we have shared it with. We will make reasonable efforts to respond as accurately and completely as possible. Life Time may decline to process unreasonable requests that are repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law. Requests may be subject to any fees and disbursements the law permits us to charge.

5.2    **Limiting the Personal Data You Provide**  
You may browse our Services without providing any Personal Data (other than data automatically collected to the extent it is considered Personal Data under applicable laws) or by limiting the Personal Data you provide. If you choose not to provide any Personal Data or limit the Personal Data you provide, you may not be able to use certain functions of the Services, such as access to the member’s website.

5.3    **Opting Out of Communications**  
Life Time may send you electronic or SMS communications marketing or advertising through the Services themselves or activities on the Services. When using our Services, you have the option of signing up for email or text communication for alerts and account notifications, and other Life Time communications, such as Life Time Insider, Flourish Newsletter, and promotions.  If at any time you would like to stop receiving the information that you have requested to receive from us, you may follow the opt-out instructions contained in any such electronic communication. Additionally, you may also manage your email preferences at any time through your account.

If you opt-out of receiving emails or promotions from us, we may still send you emails about your account or any Services you have requested or received from us, or for other customer services purposes. In addition, you may still receive emails sent by third parties through means other than our Services. You may have to unsubscribe from multiple emails before you stop receiving all communications related to events for which you registered through our Services. Please be aware that you cannot unsubscribe from update communications about our Services unless you close your account. If you wish to close your account, please email privacy@lt.life. Even after you opt-out of all communications, we will retain your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy as provided under “7. Retention of Your Personal Data”, though, we will no longer use it to contact you. However, third parties who have received your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy may still use that Personal Data to contact you in accordance with their own privacy policies.

6.     **Retention of Your Personal Data**  
We may retain your Personal Data as long as you are registered to use our Services. You may close your account by contacting us by email at [privacy@lt.life](mailto:privacy@lt.life), or by mail at the address listed under “14. Contacting Us”. However, please be aware we may retain Personal Data for an additional period as is required under applicable laws. After we delete your Personal Data, it may exist on backup or archival media or servers for an additional period of time for legal, tax, or regulatory reasons, or for legitimate and lawful business purposes.

7.     **Cookies, Web Beacons, and Other Technologies**  
7.1    **Cookies and Web Beacons Definitions**

Cookies are small data files placed onto your computer or mobile device when you visit a website which allows our Services to distinguish you from other users, allow the Services to work properly, as well as to help monitor advertising effectiveness. Web beacons work similar to cookies, however, instead of a file stored on your computer, web beacons are embedded invisibly on web pages. We use cookies, web beacons, tags, and other similar tracking technologies to track when you visit our websites and mobile applications (collectively, “ **Cookies** ”).  We also allow third parties to place Cookies on our Services to assist with advertising.

7.2    **How We Use Cookies**  
There are several reasons we use Cookies on our Services. Some of these Cookies are necessary for technical reasons and help our Services to operate as intended for your benefit (“ **Essential Cookies** ”), such as access to secure areas of the Services. Other types of Cookies are used for analytical purposes such as how our Services are being used, the effectiveness of advertising shown as you use the Services, and to customize advertising to you (“ **Analytical Cookies** ”). While these types of Cookie help us to create new features, improve on our existing Services, and provide advertisements of interest to you, our Services can function without them.

7.3    **Controlling Cookies**  
You have the right to accept or reject Cookies. You can exercise your Cookie preferences by activating the setting on your web browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some Cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies, including Essential Cookies, you may not be able to access or use all or parts of our Services. If you have not adjusted your browser setting to refuse cookies, our system will issue Cookies as soon as you visit our Services. Blocking or deleting Cookies will not prevent device identification and related data collection from occurring when you access our Services. Turning off Analytical Cookies will prevent the ability to measure the relevance and effectiveness of our Services, emails, and advertising as well as to show you tailored advertising. Other advertisements will still be displayed when you use our Services.

8.     **Children**  
The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 and its rules (“ **COPPA** ”) requires us to inform parents and legal guardians about our practices for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information from children under the age of thirteen (13). In some countries, even higher age limits may apply. Life Time does not intend to collect Personal Data from children under the age of thirteen (13), or the otherwise applicable age limit if different in your country of location. If you are aware of a user under the age of thirteen (13) who has provided Personal Data through our Services, please contact us at [privacy@lt.life](mailto:privacy@lt.life). Parents and legal guardians may choose to provide information about their children, even if under the age of thirteen (13), for the purposes of utilizing our Services.

9.     **International Privacy Laws**  
In accordance with and as permitted by applicable law and regulations, Life Time reserves the right to transfer your information, process, and store it outside your country of residence to wherever we or our third party service providers operate. By using our Services, you agree that we may use your information in the United States and other countries where Life Time operates. Please be aware that privacy laws and regulations vary between countries, including the rights of authorities to access your personal information.

10.1 **Canadian Privacy**  
The Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (“PIPEDA”) governs data privacy in Canada by regulating the commercial collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data. This Policy adopts the Ten Fair Information Principles required by PIPEDA and applies to all Personal Data submitted to or collected by Life Time. PIPEDA requires Life Time to obtain an individual’s consent to collect, use, or disclose Personal Data. Life Time only uses Personal Data for the purposes for which it was collected. If Life Time uses Personal Data for another purpose, we will obtain additional consent.

10.2 **European Privacy**  
The General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) governs data privacy in the European Union (“EU”) by creating a standardized set of data protection laws across all member countries, and giving individuals greater control over their Personal Data. The GDPR applies to (1) business that market goods and/or services to people in the EU, or (2) business that monitor the behavior of people in the EU. Life Time does not seek to market its Services to or monitor the behavior of people in the EU. If you are a person within the EU, and believe that Life Time may have some of your Personal Data, please contact us at [privacy@lt.life](mailto:privacy@lt.life). As a person in the EU, you have the right to request access to your Personal Data as well as its rectification and erasure. Please be aware we may retain Personal Data for an additional period as is required under applicable laws. After we delete your Personal Data, it may exist on backup or archival media or servers for an additional period of time for legal, tax, or regulatory reasons, or for legitimate and lawful business purposes.

10.   **Terms of Use**  
Your use of our Services, as well as any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Service, available at “[Terms of Use](https://www.mylt.life/policy/terms-of-use.html?_ga=2.197094444.1842273490.1515619138-2050217349.1514411940)” and incorporated by reference here.

11.   **Exclusions**  
11.1 **Personal Data Provided to Others**  
This Policy does not apply to any Personal Data that you provide to another user or visitor through the services or through any other means.

11.2 **Third Party Links**  
This Policy applies only to the Services we offer. The Services may contain links to other websites not operated or controlled by us (the “ **Third Party Sites** ”). The policies and procedures we described here do not apply to the Third Party Sites. The links from the Services do not imply that we endorse or review the Third Party Sites. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy policies.

11.3 **Aggregated Personal Data**  
In an ongoing effort to better understand and serve the users of our Services, we often conduct research on our customer demographics, interests, and behavior based on Personal Data and other collected information. This research may be compiled and analyzed on an aggregate basis. This aggregate information does not identify you personally and we therefore consider and treat this data as Non-Personal Data.

12.   **Changes to This Policy**  
Life Time reserves the right to update or modify this Policy at any time. If we make changes to this Policy, we will post the revised Policy to our website with a changed “Last Updated” date at the top of this Policy. All changes are effective thirty (30) days after posting. Your continued use of services following the effectiveness of any changes constitutes acceptance of those changes. If you do not agree with any of the changes to the Policy, you should cease accessing, browsing, and otherwise using of the websites or services we provide.

13.   **Contacting Us**  
If you have questions, comments, or concerns about this Policy, please contact us at:

[Privacy@lt.life](mailto:Privacy@lt.life) or  
By mail at

    ATTN: Privacy Team

    Life Time, Inc.  
    2902 Corporate Place  
    Chanhassen, MN 55317

14.   **Your California Privacy Rights**  
14.1 **Do Not Track**  
Our Services are not currently configured to respond to browsers’ “Do Not Track” signals because at this time no formal “Do Not Track” standard has been adopted.

14.2 **Shine Your Light**  
California residents may request a list of all third parties to which Life Time has disclosed certain Personal Data about you for marketing purposes. You may make one (1) request per calendar year. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response. You may request this information in writing by contacting us at the address listed under Section 14 “Contacting Us”.
